<deck name="Engineering Happiness A New Approach for Building a Joyful Life" tags='booknotes'><fields><text name='Front' sides='11' ></text><text name='Back' sides='01' ></text></fields><cards><card><text name='Front'>HAPPINESS equals WHAT I GET TODAY minus WHAT I GOT IN THE PAST</text><text name='Back'>HAPPINESS equals WHAT I GET TODAY minus WHAT I GOT IN THE PAST</text></card><card><text name='Front'>Aversion to Loss: Losses are felt more keenly than equivalent gains.</text><text name='Back'>Aversion to Loss: Losses are felt more keenly than equivalent gains.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>We have the choice to see each day as a new day full of hope and experiences. We also
                have the choice of treating each day as a "Groundhog Day" in which we basically re-live the same day
                over and over.</text><text name='Back'>We have the choice to see each day as a new day full of hope and experiences. We also have
                the choice of treating each day as a "Groundhog Day" in which we basically re-live the same day over and
                over.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>HAPPINESS equals WHAT I GET minus WHAT OTHERS GET</text><text name='Back'>HAPPINESS equals WHAT I GET minus WHAT OTHERS GET</text></card><card><text name='Front'>We adapt to both good and bad circumstances much faster than anticipated.</text><text name='Back'>We adapt to both good and bad circumstances much faster than anticipated.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>The lesson, once again, is that improving your reality will not increase happiness if
                expectations increase as well.</text><text name='Back'>The lesson, once again, is that improving your reality will not increase happiness if
                expectations increase as well.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>…, in a study titled "When Less Is More: Counterfactual Thinking and Satisfaction among
                Olympic Medalists," Tom Gilovich and his colleagues found that Olympic bronze medalists are actually
                happier than silver medalists. The silver medalists regret coming so close but not winning, whereas the
                bronze medalists compare themselves with the entire field and are thrilled to have won a medal at all.</text><text name='Back'>…, in a study titled "When Less Is More: Counterfactual Thinking and Satisfaction among
                Olympic Medalists," Tom Gilovich and his colleagues found that Olympic bronze medalists are actually
                happier than silver medalists. The silver medalists regret coming so close but not winning, whereas the
                bronze medalists compare themselves with the entire field and are thrilled to have won a medal at all.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>The conquest of satiation begins with seeing the world as a giant playground offering new
                challenges to overcome and new adventures to experience daily.</text><text name='Back'>The conquest of satiation begins with seeing the world as a giant playground offering new
                challenges to overcome and new adventures to experience daily.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>Forgiveness is the way to let go of accumulated bads.</text><text name='Back'>Forgiveness is the way to let go of accumulated bads.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>Work is far from being just a source of money; it has actually been proven to be good for
                our happiness.</text><text name='Back'>Work is far from being just a source of money; it has actually been proven to be good for
                our happiness.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>The practice of detachment, treating things that we use as if they were on loan, is
                mentally very healthy. This mitigates adaptation, and avoids the anxiety of a possible or actual loss.</text><text name='Back'>The practice of detachment, treating things that we use as if they were on loan, is
                mentally very healthy. This mitigates adaptation, and avoids the anxiety of a possible or actual loss.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>This law is called the Law of Hedonic Asymmetry by the Dutch psychologist Nico Frijda, or
                Loss Aversion by Kahneman and Tversky. According to the Law of Aversion to Loss, a ten dollar gain
                yields +2 happydons, but a ten dollar loss robs us of 5 happydons.</text><text name='Back'>This law is called the Law of Hedonic Asymmetry by the Dutch psychologist Nico Frijda, or
                Loss Aversion by Kahneman and Tversky. According to the Law of Aversion to Loss, a ten dollar gain
                yields +2 happydons, but a ten dollar loss robs us of 5 happydons.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>For example, if your flight arrives earlier than expected, you will be happy. On the
                other hand, if the flight is late, your reality is less desirable than your expectation and the mind
                produces negative feelings of annoyance.</text><text name='Back'>For example, if your flight arrives earlier than expected, you will be happy. On the other
                hand, if the flight is late, your reality is less desirable than your expectation and the mind produces
                negative feelings of annoyance.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>Re-framing activities are all those purposeful activities that make us see reality in a
                different way, reset our expectations, or create new comparisons.</text><text name='Back'>Re-framing activities are all those purposeful activities that make us see reality in a
                different way, reset our expectations, or create new comparisons.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>Sooner or later we must realize there is no station. No one place to arrive at once and
                for all. The true joy of life is in the trip. The station is only a dream. It constantly outdistances
                us. —From "The Station" by Robert Hastings</text><text name='Back'>Sooner or later we must realize there is no station. No one place to arrive at once and
                for all. The true joy of life is in the trip. The station is only a dream. It constantly outdistances
                us. —From "The Station" by Robert Hastings</text></card><card><text name='Front'>HAPPINESS IN ACTION: Select one hobby or interest and focus on developing it over time.
                It could be anything from gardening and athletics to reading and spiritual practice. Keep a diary to
                track your progress, and take time as you go to appreciate how much you've progressed.</text><text name='Back'>HAPPINESS IN ACTION: Select one hobby or interest and focus on developing it over time. It
                could be anything from gardening and athletics to reading and spiritual practice. Keep a diary to track
                your progress, and take time as you go to appreciate how much you've progressed.</text></card><card><text name='Front'>Bring to your mind some good or activity, which we will call X. Is X a basic good? Ask
                yourself the following questions: If nobody knew I'm buying or experiencing X, would I still want X?
                Will I enjoy X in the future, say five years from now, as much as I do now?</text><text name='Back'>Bring to your mind some good or activity, which we will call X. Is X a basic good? Ask
                yourself the following questions: If nobody knew I'm buying or experiencing X, would I still want X?
                Will I enjoy X in the future, say five years from now, as much as I do now?</text></card></cards></deck>